{"Topic": "Olympics", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "What do the five rings on the Olympic symbol represent?", "op1": "the five oceans", "op2": "the five continents", "op3": "the five planets", "op4": "five Greek Gods", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The five rings of the Olympic symbol are in five different colours. Red, Green, Yellow, Blue and _______", "op1": "Indigo", "op2": "Violet", "op3": "Orange", "op4": "Black", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Olympic games were held in ancient Greece in the honour of Greek God ________", "op1": "Zeus", "op2": "Uranus", "op3": "Apollo", "op4": "Jupiter", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following combination of years represents the years when the Olympic Games were not held due to the two World Wars?", "op1": "1914, 1940, 1944", "op2": "1916, 1940, 1944", "op3": "1920, 1936, 1940", "op4": "1936, 1840, 1944", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which team leads the procession of athletes at the opening ceremony of the Olympic Games?", "op1": "Hosting nation", "op2": "Greece", "op3": "Hosting nation of the next Olympic games", "op4": "Hosting nation of the previous Olympic games", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following cities have the Olympic games NOT been held twice?", "op1": "Athens", "op2": "Paris", "op3": "London", "op4": "Atlanta", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Where are the headquarters of the International Olympic Committee located?", "op1": "Lausanne, Switzerland", "op2": "Paris, France", "op3": "Athens, Greece", "op4": "Atlanta, United States", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which year were the first modern Olympic Games held?", "op1": "1900", "op2": "1896", "op3": "1904", "op4": "1892"}, {"Question": "What does the Olympic motto Citius, Altius, Fortius mean?", "op1": "1920 and 1960", "op2": "1904 and 1952", "op3": "1908 and 1948", "op4": "1904 and 1948", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Olympic Games 2012 are being held in London. In which earlier years have the Olympic Games been held in London?", "op1": "1900, Paris", "op2": "1908, London", "op3": "1904, St Louis", "op4": "1920, Antwerp", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which year did women participate for the first time in modern Olympic Games?", "op1": "Manlock and Wendeville", "op2": "Wenlock and Mandeville", "op3": "Fuwa, the dolls", "op4": "Athena and Phevos", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What are the names of the mascots of the London Olympics 2012?", "op1": "1900, Paris", "op2": "1908, London", "op3": "1920, Antwerp", "op4": "1928, Amsterdam", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "At which of the following Olympic Games was the Olympic flag flown for the first time?", "op1": "Le Marqu\u00e9s de Samaranch", "op2": "Pierre de Coubertin", "op3": "Demetrius Vikelas", "op4": "Ferenc Kem\u00e9ny", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is known as the Father of Modern Olympics?", "op1": "Germany", "op2": "Great Britain", "op3": "United States of America", "op4": "Greece", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following countries won the maximum number of medals at the first Olympic Games in 1896?", "op1": "1896, Athens", "op2": "1908, London", "op3": "1928, Amsterdam", "op4": "1920, Antwerp", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the Olympic Games was the Olympic flame introduced for the first time?", "op1": "Hosting nation", "op2": "Greece", "op3": "Hosting nation of the next Olympic games", "op4": "Hosting nation of the previous Olympic games", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which team is at the end of the procession of athletes at the opening ceremony of the Olympic Games?", "op1": "Chinese", "op2": "French", "op3": "Spanish", "op4": "German", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which language other than English is the Official language of the International Olympic Committee?", "op1": "Share the Spirit", "op2": "One World One Dream", "op3": "Welcome Home", "op4": "Inspire a Generation", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "According to the Olympic charter, the duration of the competitions of the Olympic Games shall not exceed -", "op1": "20 days", "op2": "15 days", "op3": "12 days", "op4": "16 days", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "At which of the following Olympic Games was the Olympic oath taken for the first time?", "op1": "1936, Berlin", "op2": "1920, Antwerp", "op3": "1968, Mexico City", "op4": "1956, Melbourne", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "At which of the following Olympics were gold medals made of pure gold last awarded?", "op1": "1912", "op2": "1920", "op3": "1936", "op4": "1948", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following athletes has won the maximum number of individual gold medals at a single Olympics?", "op1": "Mark Sptiz", "op2": "Michael Phelps", "op3": "Carl Lewis", "op4": "Matt Biondi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following in 1896 became the first champion of the modern Olympic Games?", "op1": "Norman Pitchard", "op2": "Paul Masson", "op3": "Carl Schumann", "op4": "James Connolly", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first person to complete the 100 m event in under 10 seconds?", "op1": "Jim Hines", "op2": "Jesse Ownes", "op3": "Usain Bolt", "op4": "Ben Johnson", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following gymnasts was the first to be awarded a perfect score of 10 in an Olympic gymnastic event?", "op1": "Elena Mukhina", "op2": "Nellie Kim", "op3": "Nadia Comaneci", "op4": "Yelena Davydova", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first female Olympic champion?", "op1": "Helen Jackson", "op2": "Charlotte Cooper", "op3": "Agnes Morton", "op4": "Louise Martin", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the Olympic flame lit before the start of the Olympic Games every four years?", "op1": "Temple of Zeus", "op2": "Temple of Diana", "op3": "Temple of Hera", "op4": "Temple of Artemis", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Among the following Indians, who was the first to win an individual medal at the Olympics?", "op1": "K.D. Jadhav", "op2": "Leander Paes", "op3": "Rajyavardhan Singh Rathore", "op4": "Karnam Malleswari", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of these Olympic Games did Dhyanchand captain the gold medal winning Indian hockey team?", "op1": "1956, Melbourne", "op2": "1948, London", "op3": "1928, Amsterdam", "op4": "1936, Berlin", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who among the following is the lone winner of gold medal from India in the Olympics?", "op1": "Abhinav Bindra", "op2": "Vijender Kumar", "op3": "Sushil Kumar", "op4": "Rajyavardhan Rathore", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "When were the first recorded Olympics held ?", "op1": "825 BC", "op2": "776 BC", "op3": "320 BC", "op4": "80 AD", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who won the gold medal for 400 metres run at two consecutive Olympic games?", "op1": "Michael Johnson", "op2": "Carl Lewis", "op3": "Alvin Harrison", "op4": "Gregory Haughton", "Answer": 3}]}